Guide to the Yale Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Alphabetical, Series I
  - Shepard, Lorrin A.: letters to family and others, 1919-1928 (Box 17, Folder 687)
    Lorrin Shepard graduated from Yale College in 1914 and from Columbia Medical School in 1917. Following their marriage in 1919, he and his wife, Virginia, sailed to Turkey, where they worked with the Near East Relief unit in Aintab (now Gaziantep) providing medical services to Armenian refugees and others. The letters, written by the Shepards to family and friends, describe medical relief efforts in Turkey during the Turkish War of Independence (1919-1923), the Turkish-Armenian War (1920), and the ongoing genocide against Armenians in the crumbling Ottoman Empire following World War I. Shepard served as the director of the American Hospital in Istanbul from 1927-1957. At Yale, following their return from Turkey, he served as director of the International Student Center from 1957-1959, and as Assistant to the University Secretary from 1959 until his retirement in 1963.
  - Sherman, Philemon T.: typed reminiscences of life at Yale, undated (Box 17, Folder 688)
  - Sherwood, William B.: ALS to J.A. Baldwin, 1829 (Box 17, Folder 689)
  - Shipman, Nathaniel: ALS to A. Johnson, 1859 (Box 17, Folder 690)
  - Silliman, Benjamin (1816-1885): carbon typescript of "They Danced on the Table: A Story of the Silliman House, Hillhouse Avenue" by George Dudley Seymour, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 691)
  - Silliman, Benjamin (1849-1901): ALS from J. King Goodrich: Transferred to Silliman Family Mas 450 11/82, 1868 (Box 17, Folder 692)
  - Singletary, John: essay on the "Parallel between Gibbon and Hume", Circa 1813 (Box 17, Folder 693)
  - Sizer, Theodore: Transferred to the Theodore Sizer Papers, Mss 453 (Box 17, Folder 694)
  - Skinner, Aaron N.: 2 ALS and electrostatic copies of scholastic reports for William B. Cleaveland: Transferred to Bristol Family Papers Mss 101. 8/17/82, 1845-1851 (Box 17, Folder 695)
  - Slack, William Samuel: typescript of "Memories of a Yale Man: Henry Richmond Slack of the Class of 1855", undated (Box 17, Folder 696)
  - Smith, David: ALS to Wyllys Warner with typescript, ALS from Jeremiah Day, 1840, 1848 (Box 17, Folder 697)
  - Smith, Junius: "A Short Oration read at the dissolution of the Philocretian Society", 1800 (Box 17, Folder 698)
  - Smith, Nathan: bill to Mr. Hartshorn: Transferred to Misc MSS S, undated (Box 17, Folder 699)
  - Smith, Richard: ALS to C. Birne, photostat of same, 1827 (Box 17, Folder 700)
  - Smith, Robert W.: ALS to his mother, 2 essays, 1844-1845 (Box 17, Folder 701)
  - Smyth (Smith), Ralph D.: term bills, expense memorandum, essays, records of the V.O.C. Society, invitation, 1823-1830 (Box 17, Folder 702)
  - Smyth (Smith), Walter: acceptance letter from Yale, term bills, invitation to Alpha Delta Phi, other Yale memorabilia, 1859-1863 (Box 17, Folder 703)
  - Snyder, M.B.: ALS to Josiah Willard Gibbs with program from the International Electrical Exhibition, 1884 (Box 17, Folder 704)
  - Spalding, Rufus P.: ALS to Maurice Wakeman, ALS to Evening Journal, 1867 (Box 17, Folder 705)
  - Spaulding, Frank E.: ALS to his son, notes and outlines concerning the Department of Education, Yale University, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 706)
  - Spence, Thomas Adams: ALS to President Nott (Union College) from Thomas R.P. Spence concerning his son, 1828 (Box 17, Folder 707)
  - Stagg, Amos Alonzo: correspondence, news clippings, other material related to Stagg, 1891-1965 (Box 17, Folder 708)
  - Staples, Seth P.: ALS to Mary L. Staples, 1861 (Box 17, Folder 709)
  - Stanley, Anthony D.: correspondence, essay, 1830-1852, undated (Box 17, Folder 710)
  - Stanford, Arthur W.: typed manuscript, "The No no Utai and Kyogen", correspondence on Korean religion, 1909, [1917?], undated (Box 17, Folder 711)
  - Stebbins, Daniel: ALS to A. Plant, ALS to John Woodworth, 1838, 1848, 1852 (Box 17, Folder 712)
  - Stedman, James: 2 ALS to Nancy Clarke, 1806 (Box 17, Folder 713)
  - Stevens, Shepherd: Transferred to Shepherd Stevens Papers, Mss 865 (Box 17, Folder 714)
  - Stewart, George: TL from Luther Weigle with enclosures, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 715)
  - Stiles, Betsey: letter in the third person to Mr. or Mrs. Hillhouse -- Transferred to Hillhouse Family Papers, Mss 282, 1781 (Box 17, Folder 716)
  - Stiles, Robert A.: ALS to Mrs. Morris, announcement of election to Phi Beta Kappa, certificate of admission to Yale, Class of 1859 announcement, 1855-1895 (Box 17, Folder 717)
  - Stiles, William A.: ALS to a classmate, 1859 (Box 17, Folder 718)
  - Stiles, William H.: ALS to James F. Cooper, 1844 (Box 17, Folder 719)
  - Stillman, Elizabeth P. (Goodrich): typed sketch about her life, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 720)
  - Stimson, Henry A.: ALS to Lovell Hall, 1864 (Box 17, Folder 721)
  - Stimson, Henry L.: TLS to George Parmly Day, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 722)
  - Stimson, John Ward: drawings and sketches of Yale student life, Circa 1872 (Box 17, Folder 723)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps: Transferred to the Anson Phelps Stokes Papers, Mss 299 (Box 17, Folder 724)
  - Storrs, Henry A.: ALS to [S.L. South___?], 1829 (Box 17, Folder 725)
  - Street, Augustus R.: ALS to Alexander Bliss, 1814 (Box 17, Folder 726)
  - Strong, Adonijah: transcript of a letter written to his son, 1803 (Box 17, Folder 727)
  - Strong, Cyprian: geometry notebook, 1761 (Box 17, Folder 728)
  - Strong, Nehemiah: "Ad Classem Recentium in Collegio Yalensi Salutem"; papers re his wife, Lydia (Smith) Strong and Andrew Burr, her first husband; memoranda and fragment re Yale College, 1761-1778, undated (Box 17, Folder 729)
  - Sumner, William Graham: Transferred to the William Graham Sumner Papers, Mss 291 (Box 17, Folder 730)
  - Sweet, H. Gordon: typed sermon, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 731)
  - Sylvester, Richard S.: TLS to Donald Wing, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 732)
  - Saurer, David Lee: "Women at Yale" and related material, 1969 (Box 18)
  - Taft, Arthur I.: correspondence, 1918-1920 (Box 19, Folder 733)
  - Taft, Horace D.: typewritten script from motion picture film, 1933 (Box 19, Folder 734)
  - Tarbox, Increase M.: Transferred to Increase Miles Tarbox Papers, Mss 1153 (Box 19, Folder 735)
  - Taylor, Harry K.: papers pertaining to his activities as a YMCA secretary in France during World War I, cap, 1918 (Box 19, Folder 736)
  - Taylor, Nathaniel W. (1786-1858): ALS to Julius Barnes, handwritten text of sermon preached "at Mr. Porter's Installation", 1836, 1843 (Box 19, Folder 737)
  - Taylor, Nathaniel W.: letter to his brother, 1828 December 1 (Box 19, Folder 737)
  - Taylor, Nathaniel W.: journal of a voyage to Hurd's Island, 1857-1859 (Box 19, Folder 738)
  - Taylor, William H.: ALS to Elbert B. Moore concerning a riot involving undergraduates and townsmen, 1854 (Box 19, Folder 739)
  - Tener, Kinley J.: ALS to Mrs. Munro, 1915 (Box 19, Folder 740)
  - Thacher, Thomas A.: correspondence,: Transferred to Thomas A. Thacher Papers, Ms. Gr. 1697, 1862-1884 (Box 19, Folder 741)
  - Thompson, Augustus C.: 2 ALS to H. Mitchell and unidentified correspondent, 1854 (Box 19, Folder 742)
  - Thompson, Daniel V.: "The University Press," carbon copy with 2 copies of first 2 pages of printed text, inscribed "For Carl Rollins from Dan - 1939" (Box 19, Folder 743)
  - Thompson, William A.: extracts from his autobiography, Circa 1782 (Box 19, Folder 744)
  - Thompson, William M.: 3 ALS to his mother, 1833-1836 (Box 19, Folder 745)
  - Thresher, Harold Hayward: "'Autobiography' of a Non-Great by Third Parties who did not then wist of this their Authorship", 1902-1967 (Box 19, Folder 746)
  - Tinker, Chauncey Brewster: ALS from Percival M___, stock certificate from Brick Row Book Shop, 1921, 1926 (Box 19, Folder 747)
  - Titus, John: ALS to Samuel J. Hitchcock, 1814 (Box 19, Folder 748)
  - Tourtelotte, Sarah A.: drawing of Yale College, undated (Box 19, Folder 749)
  - Townsend, Henry C.: correspondence, 1840-1873 (Box 19, Folder 750)
  - Tracy, Rogers: Transferred to Tracy Family Papers, Mss 816 (Box 19, Folder 751)
  - Trumbull, John: signed announcement of his exhibition, 1835 (Box 19, Folder 752)
  - Trumbull, Leverett B.: epitaph, 1807 (Box 19, Folder 753)
  - Trump, Franklin: transcripts of letters to his family, 1864-1866 (Box 19, Folder 754)
  - Tully, William: ALS to F.B. Dexter from E.L. Tully, 1895 (Box 19, Folder 755)
  - Tunney, Gene: TLS to George Parmly Day, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 756)
  - Tuttle, William R.: TLS to Charles Seymour with fingerprints taken in Professor Sumner's Anthropology class, 1941 (Box 19, Folder 757)
  - Tweedy, Harold L.: typed report on junior year scholarship in Germany, 1931-1932 (Box 19, Folder 758)
  - Twining, Edward Henry: letters of recommendation from Yale faculty, 1851-1872 (Box 19, Folder 759)
  - Twombly, Alexander S.: Transferred to Alexander S. Twombly Papers, Mss 1163 (Box 19, Folder 760)
  - Twombly, Henry Bancroft: "Personal Reminiscences of a Yale Football Player of the Early Eighties", undated (Box 19, Folder 761)
  - Tyler, John: address to a Masonic meeting, undated (Box 19, Folder 762)
  - Upham, Nathan: ALS to Laurens Upham, 1850 (Box 19, Folder 763)
  - Vaill, George D.: correspondence and other material relating to his student days at Yale, 1931-1948 (Box 19, Folder 764)
  - Van Rensselear, Cortlandt: ALS to John D. P. Down, 1831 (Box 19, Folder 765)
  - Varnum, Joseph B.: ALS to his father, 1858 (Box 19, Folder 766)
  - Viele, Dorr: ALS to "Tinker", 1954 (Box 19, Folder 767)
  - Vose, George: 2 ALS to Henry R. Hinckley: Transferred H.B. Hinckley Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 1230, 1860 (Box 19, Folder 768)
  - Wade, Robert B.: ALS from M.A. Doran, 1893 (Box 20, Folder 769)
  - Walden, Howard T.: ALS to his brother, Percy T. Walden, 1887 (Box 20, Folder 770)
  - Waldo, Leonard: ANS to Prof. Loomis: Transferred to Elias Loomis Family Papers MSS 331, 1881 (Box 20, Folder 771)
  - Walker, G.L.: Transferred to Divinity Library (Box 20, Folder 772)
  - Walworth, Arthur C: "Freshman Year, A Colloquy," manuscript of a play, [1865] (Box 20, Folder 773)
  - Wanning, Andrews: newspaper article about Col. Edward House Collection at Yale University Library, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 774)
  - Ward, George O.: correspondence and biographical material concerning Nelson Wheeler, 1917, undated (Box 20, Folder 775)
  - Warner, A. & Warner, R.: Transferred to Selden Warner Papers, Mss 536 (Box 20, Folder 776)
  - Warner, Charles D.: ALS to Franklin B. Dexter, ALS to Mr. Jay, 1872, 1898 (Box 20, Folder 777)
  - Warner, Wyllys: 11 letters and documents by or, relating to Wyllys Warner, manuscript copy of resolution on the death of Wyllys Warner by Trustees of Goffe St. School, 1830-1869, 1869 (Box 20, Folder 778)
  - Warren, Stanley P.: essay, [ca. 1931?] (Box 20, Folder 779)
  - Washburn, E.T.: Transferred to Joseph Washburn Papers, Mss 1053 (Box 20, Folder 780)
  - Washburn, J.: Transferred to Joseph Washburn Papers, Mss 1053 (Box 20, Folder 781)
  - Washburn, Joseph: Transferred to Joseph Washburn Papers, Mss 1053 (Box 20, Folder 782)
  - Washington, George: copy of London Chronicle containing announcement of Yale conferring honorary Doctorate of Laws degree upon George Washington (p. 10), correspondence concerning newspaper announcement, 1781, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 783)
  - Waterman, Elijah: 2 photostatic copies of ALS to Mr. Allen, 1790 (Box 20, Folder 784)
  - Watson, James: tax registration, 1796 (Box 20, Folder 785)
  - Wayland, Francis: Transferred to Wayland Family Papers, Mss 1067 (Box 20, Folder 786)
  - Webb, Isaac: open letter of introduction written for Isaac Webb by Jeremiah Day, typewritten biographical sketch of Webb, 1840, undated (Box 20, Folder 787)
  - Webster, Noah: circular soliciting subscriptions to Friends of Literature in the United States, manuscript copy of Webster's will: Transferred to Webster Family Papers Mss 527 5/83, 1807, 1839 (Box 20, Folder 788)
  - Webster Prize (Yale University): "An Extract from the Progress of Liberty, A Poem", 1793 (Box 20, Folder 789)
  - Weed, Lewis H.: correspondence concerning Weed, printed copy of portrait, 1970, undated (Box 20, Folder 790)
  - Weeks, William J.: copy of wardrobe list, correspondence concerning wardrobe list, 1840, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 791)
  - Welch, Gideon Higgins: 24 ALS (photostatic copies) to his grandfather, 1864-1869 (Box 20, Folder 792)
  - Welch, Theodore F.: notebook, 1866 (Box 20, Folder 793)
  - Welles, Charles Bradford: typed manuscript, "History of the 441st Strategic Intelligence Research and Analysis Team, U.S.A.", undated (Box 20, Folder 794)
  - Welles, Lemuel A.: TLS to Anne S. Pratt, TLS to Anne S. Pratt from Marjorie Watkins, 1932, 1933 (Box 20, Folder 795)
  - Wells, Peter: pen and ink drawing, undated (Box 20, Folder 796)
  - Wetmore, Charles H.: manuscript copy of his agreement with Dr. Burritt; 2 ALS to Wetmore from his brother, Victory Wetmore; document signed by Timothy Dwight dismissing Wetmore "in good standing"; p. 117-118, 121-124 detached from "Wetmore Memorial": Transferred to Wetmore Family Papers MSS 548 12/83 NR, 1801-1806, undated (Box 20, Folder 797)
  - Wharton, Francis: ALS to Jonathan N. Purviance, 1850 (Box 20, Folder 798)
  - Wheaton, Nathaniel S.: manuscript pamphlet, "Notes from Disputations: Ought foreign immigrations to be encouraged?", 1813 (Box 20, Folder 799)
  - Wheeler, Arthur M.: Transferred to John W. Sterling Papers, Mss 1097 (Box 20, Folder 800)
  - Wheeler, J[ohn] Davenport: ALS to Professor John F. Weir, 1913 (Box 20, Folder 801)
  - Wheeler, [William]: diploma, 1857 (Box 20, Folder 802)
  - White, Andrew D.: TLS to Andrew Keogh with carbon of Keogh's reply on same page, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 803)
  - Whiting, F.S.: ALS to Henry A. Clark, 1832 (Box 20, Folder 804)
  - Whiting, Myles: signed manuscript poem (no title), undated (Box 20, Folder 805)
  - Whitney, J.S.: Transferred to William D. Whitney Family Papers, Mss 555 (Box 20, Folder 806)
  - Whitney, J.S.: Transferred to William D. Whitney Family Papers, Mss 555 (Box 20, Folder 807)
  - Whiton, James M.: correspondence, 1901-1912 (Box 20, Folder 808)
  - Whiton, James M.: "Memoranda of Yale College, 1849-1853", "Thoughts on Junior Year", "Brevisvita, ara longa", unsigned poem, "The Globe Trotter", memorabilia, 1853-1915, undated (Box 20, Folder 809)
  - Whiton, James M.: Semi-centennial commemoration of the first Harvard-Yale regatta: correspondence, clippings, memorabilia, 1902-1903 (Box 20, Folder 810)
  - Whittmore, Williams H.: ALS to George G. Parker, 1824 (Box 20, Folder 811)
  - Whittlesey, Elisha: ALS to Mary Potter, 1776 (Box 20, Folder 812)
  - Wickham, J.D.: ALS to his father, Daniel H. Wickham, 1816 (Box 20, Folder 813)
  - "The Widow and Her Child," unsigned poem, 1838 (Box 20, Folder 814)
  - Wight, Charles A.: ALS to the Librarian of Yale University, 1909 (Box 20, Folder 815)
  - Wilbur, Seth T.: ALS (photostatic copy) to his sister, Saloma Wilbur, 1837 (Box 20, Folder 816)
  - Wilcox, Herbert B.: typed resolution, TLS from Charles E. Farr, 1915 (Box 20, Folder 817)
  - Wildman, Horatio: ALS to his mother, 1845 (Box 20, Folder 818)
  - Williams, Henry S.: T.L. (carbon) to Prof. E.L. Nichols with carbon of typescript of "The Founding of Sigma Xi"; program for Sigma Xi initiation, Cornell University, with manuscript notes and signatures on inside, 1908, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 819)
  - Williams, Nathan W.: 2 ALS to Sylvester W. Turner, 1887, 1893 (Box 20, Folder 820)
  - Williams, Ralph O.: army discharge paper, 1864 (Box 20, Folder 821)
  - Williams, Stephen C.: 2 ALS to Charles R. Alsop, 1921 (Box 20, Folder 822)
  - Williams, T.W.: ALS to unnamed correspondent, 1835 (Box 20, Folder 823)
  - Williams, Thomas: 3 commonplace books, Circa 1750-1751 (Box 20, Folder 824)
  - Willis, Nathaniel P.: ALS to J.C. Odiorne: Transferred to Yale Misc Mss 156, 1822 (Box 20, Folder 825)
  - Willson, Theodore B.: letter of introduction from Timothy Dwight, 1890 (Box 20, Folder 826)
  - Wilson, Caroline: ALS to Noah Porter, 1889 (Box 20, Folder 827)
  - Winslow, Hubbard: 2 ALS to Captain Sears, 1863 (Box 20, Folder 828)
  - Wise, William C.: "A Skipper's Letters to his Wife Fifty Years Ago": letters of Rear-Admiral William C. Wise aboard the U.S.S. Yale, 1898 (Box 21, Folder 829)
  - Wiseman, Robert R.: oil painting of Handsome Dan, undated (Box 21, Folder 830)
  - Winthrop, Theodore: ALS to his uncle, 1851 (Box 21, Folder 831)
  - Withington, Leonard: "A Dialogue in Two Acts", 1814 (Box 21, Folder 832)
  - Woodbridge, Benjamin: salutatorian address (in Latin), 1740 (Box 21, Folder 833)
  - Woodbridge, John: Master's degree from Yale College, 1734 (Box 21, Folder 834)
  - Woodbridge, William C.: ALS from R. Goodman, 1833 (Box 21, Folder 835)
  - Woodruff, Lorande Loss: ALS to Hollon Farr with a reprint and photograph about the Yale College microscope, 1942-1943 (Box 21, Folder 836)
  - Woodward, Rufus: address on leaving his class at Yale College (transcript), 1822 (Box 21, Folder 837)
  - Woolsey, John Munro: ALS to Mr. and Mrs. George Parmly Day: Transferred to George P. Day 1935 Papers, Mss Group No 174 (Box 21, Folder 838)
  - Worcester, Edwin D.: Transferred to Edwin D. Worcester Papers, Mss 563 (Box 21, Folder 839)
  - Wordin, Nathaniel E.: 3 ALS to "Ben", 1869 (Box 21, Folder 840)
  - Worrilow, William H.: 2 ALS to Louise Allen, 1944-1945 (Box 21, Folder 841)
  - Wright, Charles: letters to Wright, 1884-1885 (Box 21, Folder 842)
  - Yale Co-operative Corporation: annual reports, 1901-1904 (Box 21, Folder 843)
  - Yale, Elihu: Transferred to Elihu Yale Papers, Mss 566 (Box 21, Folder 844)
  - Yale Publishing Association: typed minutes of the Governors, 1910-1938 (Box 21, Folder 845)
  - Yale University, Class of 1786: class play, 1784 (Box 21, Folder 845a)
  - Young, Mason: petition nominating Young for a position on the Yale Corporation, 1873 (Box 21, Folder 846)
  - Yung, Bartlett: TLS to Jane (Bartlett) Kellogg, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 847)
- Numerical, Series II
  - No. 1: Dutton, Matthew Rice (1783-1825): diary and notebook including an essay on Persia and a note on his will, 1805-1808, 1825 (Box 22)
  - No. 2: Gilman, Daniel Coit (1831-1908): scrapbook containing correspondence and printed matter concerning the Exhibition of Works of Art held at Yale College, 1858 Jun 18-Aug 14, 1858 May 15-September 28 (Box 22)
  - No. 3: Allen, Alldis Samuel (1803-1833): ALS (xerox) to his sister, [1827] March 14 (Box 22)
  - No. 4: Bird, James (1826-1901): ALS (xerox) to his cousin Edward J. Tenney (transferred to Isaac Bird Pps, MS. GR. f82), 1847 November 9 (Box 22)
  - No. 5: Carrington, George (1796-1843): ALS to Prudential Committee of the Corporation of Yale College from Carrington, Henry Herrick, and other students, [ca. 1822] (Box 22)
  - No. 6: Case, Albertson (1843-): ALS to his father, 1863 March 8 (Box 22)
  - No. 7: Cutter, Jonas (1791-1820): 2 ALS (xerox) to Benjamin F. Heywood, 1813 November 21, 1814 February 28 (Box 22)
  - No. 8: Hickerson, Sereno Dwight (1823-1909): ALS to Miss E. A. Nickerson, ALS to Ellen M. Nickerson, 1843 July 26, [October 7] (Box 22)
  - No. 9: Yale University. Saybrook College: draft of letter from [Elliot Dunlap Smith] to Everett V. Meeks concerning activities in the College, with draft summary of the letter by Meeks, 1946 March 1 (Box 22)
  - No. 10: Yale University. Theological Atheneum: by-laws and lists of subscribers, 1829 January (Box 22)
  - No. 11: Yale University. Pundits: book of minutes, 1903 October-1911 April (Box 23)
    General
    This material can be found in Pundits, Yale University, Records, RU 308, box 1.
  - No. 12: Holley, Horace (1781-1827): 16 ALS (xerox) to his father, Luther Holley, and other family members, 1799 December 3-1802 November 22 (Box 23)
  - No. 13: Mixter, George Webber (-): circular letter (2 copies) to members of the Class of 1895S, with 25 photographs, 1896 October 30 (Box 23)
  - No. 14: Yale Club of India: correspondence file, 1966-1973 (Box 23)
  - No. 15: Shockley, William (1910-): material relating to the Shockley debate controversy at Yale, 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - No. 16: Cowley, William Harold (1899-): TM (xerox), "Thomas Clap and the Founding of Yale", TLS (xerox) to John S. Whitehead, 1971 May 25, June 4 (Box 23)
  - No. 17: Kapelsohn, Emanuel (1952-): TM (xerox), "Developments in Conditioning Methods for American Collegiate Rowing, 1850-1900", 1974 April 24 (Box 23)
  - No. 17: Kilpatrick, Donald G. (-): TM (electrostatic copy), "The Emergence of Organized Athletics in Nineteenth Century American Society: The Yale Experience", 1977 (Box 23)
  - No. 18: Sommer, Frank Henry (1922-): TM, "Analysis of the Social Structure of an Institution (1940-1943)", undated (Box 23)
  - No. 19: Yale University. Executive Committee of Yale College: Transferred to Yale Archives
  - No. 20: Rogers, James Gamble III (-): TM (xerox), "James Gamble Rogers-Yale Architect," by James G. Rogers, III, 1968 April 30 (Box 24)
  - No. 21: Peet, Stephen (1797-1855): AM (electrostatic copy) journal containing notes, essays, and orations, 1821 October 15-1822 June 25 (Box 24)
  - No. 22: Zager, William Frederick (1945-): TM, "Dwight Memorial Chapel, Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut", 1964 December 18 (Box 24)
  - No. 23: Tuttle, Henry Emerson (1890-1946): Transferred to Henry Emerson Tuttle Papers (Box 24)
  - No. 24: Wagner, Henry Raup (1862-1957): TMS (photocopy), "Some Reminiscences of My Early Life", 1951 March (Box 24)
  - No. 25: Taft, William Howard (1857-1930): Transferred to William Howard Taft Papers (Box 24)
  - No. 26: Yale University. Divinity School. Rhetorical Society: treasurer's book, 1835-1853 (Box 24)
  - No. 27: Schwartz, William Jay (1952-): IMS, "The United States and the Refugee Crisis, 1933-1938", 1974 April 22 (Box 24)
  - No. 28: Bird, Isaac (-): ALS "To the undergraduate members of the Church in Y[ale] College," signed also by Eleazer Brainard and Samuel Spring (transferred to Isaac Bird Pps, MS. GR. # 82), 1819 November 18 (Box 24)
  - No. 29: Liebman, James Steven (1952-): TMS, "The Shower of Divine Blessings in This Day: the Revival of Religion in New England, 1761-1765", 1974 April 22 (Box 24)
  - No. 30: Kasimer, Joseph Henry (1950-): TMS, "George Fitzhugh: Philosopher of the Old South" 1970 spring (Box 24)
  - No. 31: Whittelsey, Charles Mills (1842-1917): AMS, "Solutions of Prize Problems proposed to the Class of Sixty Four. C.M. Whittelsy-1st Prize", 1862 October 15 (Box 24)
  - No. 32: Keller, Deane (1901-): TL (draft) to Gerald Freund, ALS to Henry Chauncey, TMS, his remembrances of Yale University's School of the Fine Arts, 1969 December 22, 1975 January 25, undated (Box 24)
  - No. 33: McAllister, Jef (-): TMS (xerox), "Yale Students of the 1920's and Their Attitudes: A Study of the Class of 1928", 1974 December 11 (Box 25)
  - No. 34: Bernstein, Michael A. (-): TMS (xerox), "To Win the War: Defense Research at Yale University (1939-1950)", 1974 April 14 (Box 25)
  - No. 35: Harned, Herbert Spencer (1888-): Transferred to Herbert Spencer Harned Papers (Box 25)
  - No. 36: [Bittker, Ann] (-): TMS (xerox), untitled biographical sketch of Frank Richard Oastler, undated (Box 25)
  - No. 37: Yale University. Yale Amateurs: invitation to a performance and letters in reply to an invitation to a performance, 1933-1934 (Box 25)
  - No. 38: Henning, Basil Duke (1910-): Transferred to Basil Duke Henning Papers (Box 25)
  - No. 39: Hanf, Noel Erskine (1940-): TMS, "Secretary of State Henry L. Stimson and the Sino-Soviet Dispute of 1929", 1962 May 1 (Box 25)
  - No. 40: Yeager, Charles Lewis (1930-): AMS, "The Forty-first Point", 9 newspaper clippings, 1953 January 9 (Box 25)
  - No. 41: Alling, Lewis (-): ALS to the President of Yale College (Jeremiah Day), from the Yale College "sweepers"; signed by Alling, John Kay, and Niles Sperry, [1836] (Box 25)